<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Welcome to CMIT! on CMIT</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/</link><description>Recent content in Welcome to CMIT! on CMIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 11:04:51 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Abel Prize Talks</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/abelprize/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/abelprize/</guid><description>The Abel Prize Talks. Abel Prize 2022 This year, on March 23, the Abel Prize was awarded to Dennis Parnell Sullivan “for his groundbreaking contributions to topology in its broadest sense, and in particular its algebraic, geometric and dynamical aspects”. To celebrate and honour this momentous occasion, the club is hosting this year's Abel Prize Talk in collaboration with Jain University, Bangalore and Mathematical Sciences Institute, Belagavi. The lecture will be delivered by Prof Siddhartha Gadgil, Indian Institute of Science, Bangalore, on April 29 at 10:30 AM IST.</description></item><item><title>Semi-direct product of categories and a Schur’s lemma for categorical representations (Part II)</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/blog/talk-semidirect-product-of-categories-saikat-chatterjee/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 11:04:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/blog/talk-semidirect-product-of-categories-saikat-chatterjee/</guid><description>We are delighted to be back with the second part of the talk by Dr. Saikat Chatterjee, School of Mathematics, IISER Thiruvananthapuram. Please note that this will be a follow-up talk to the first lecture delivered during CMIT&amp;rsquo;s third foundation anniversary, $S^3$. To know more about the first talk, click here.
Speaker: Dr. Saikat Chatterjee, SoM, IISER Thiruvananthapuram
Title: Semi-direct product of categories and a Schur’s lemma for categorical representations (Part II).</description></item><item><title>Two-part lecture series: Rational approximations and Subspace Theorem | Some applications of Subspace Theorem</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/blog/two-part-lecture-series-thangadurai/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 10:00:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/blog/two-part-lecture-series-thangadurai/</guid><description>It gives us immense pleasure to announce our next speaker in the ‘Two-part Lecture Series’, jointly hosted by CMIT and the School of Mathematics, IISER Thiruvananthapuram.
Kindly note that the two-part lectures will be delivered in a manner to cover the necessary basics in the first part of the talk, while the second part builds upon the same and continues.
The following two-part lecture will be delivered by Prof R. Thangadurai, Harish Chandra Research Institute, on April 11 and 13, 2022, at 11:30 AM.</description></item><item><title>Two-part lecture series: Development of the Theory of Equations | Polynomials, Matrices, and Linear Recurrences over Galois Fields</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/blog/two-part-lecture-series-sudhir-ghorpade/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 10:00:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/blog/two-part-lecture-series-sudhir-ghorpade/</guid><description>After a long hiatus, it gives us immense pleasure to announce our next speaker in the ‘Two-part Lecture Series’, jointly hosted by CMIT and the School of Mathematics, IISER Thiruvananthapuram.
Kindly note that the two-part lectures will be delivered in a manner to cover the necessary basics in the first part of the talk, while the second part builds upon the same and continues.
The following two-part lecture will be delivered by Prof Sudhir Ghorpade, Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay, on March 30, 2022, at 5:00 PM and on April 1, 2022, at 11:30 AM.</description></item><item><title>CMIT talk series: An introduction to q-analysis</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/blog/talk-q-analysis-manjil-saikia/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 11:04:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/blog/talk-q-analysis-manjil-saikia/</guid><description>As part of our talk series, we are glad to announce a new talk next week by Dr. Manjil Saikia, from Cardiff University, UK. Please find further talk details below.
Speaker: Dr. Manjil Saikia, Postdoctoral Research Associate, Cardiff University, UK.
Title: An introduction to $q$-analysis.
Venue and time: Google Meet (online) | 02:30 PM (GMT +5:30), Wednesday, 3rd November, 2021.
Abstract: There is no formal definition of q-analysis, some prefer to just refer to it as $q$-series, a subject consisting of identities between certain kinds of sums and products.</description></item><item><title>Two-part lecture series: Financial Risk Management | Transitioning to a Decarbonized Economy</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/blog/two-part-lecture-series-siddhartha-pratim-chakrabarty/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 11:04:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/blog/two-part-lecture-series-siddhartha-pratim-chakrabarty/</guid><description>We are extremely glad to announce the next lecture in our ‘Two-part Lecture Series’, to be jointly hosted by CMIT and the School of Mathematics, IISER Thiruvananthapuram.
Kindly note that the two-part lectures will be delivered in a manner to cover the necessary basics in the first part of the talk, while the second part builds upon the same and continues.
This time, the two-part lecture will be delivered by Prof.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 14:47:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/about/</guid><description>About the club. CMIT is a student-run community. Feel free to contact us regarding anything relevant, whether it is about information regarding the club, suggestions on new events, or general comments. If you want to propose problems for the Weekly Problems Contest, volunteer as a peer math discussion mentor, or want to be a speaker for the Talk Series, mail us at mathsclub [at] iisertvm [dot] ac [dot] in. The ‘Club of Mathematics, IISER Thiruvananthapuram’ is recognized officially by the Mathematics Department at IISER Thiruvananthapuram, and is faculty-supervised.</description></item><item><title>Archive of events</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/events/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 14:47:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/events/</guid><description>Events at CMIT. This page contains information about all upcoming events at CMIT, and an archive of all the past events. Visit our blog and social media handles to know more and connect with us. If you have a suggestion or query, drop us an email at mathsclub [at] iisertvm [dot] ac [dot] in.
Note: CMIT Peer Discussion Sessions are logged separately here. Vasanth 2022 March 14 $\sim$ 20: CMIT celebrates International $\pi$ Week 2022 > details</description></item><item><title>CMIT Activities</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/activities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 14:47:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/activities/</guid><description>Activities at CMIT. Know more about the activities at CMIT.
Talk Series Delivered by faculties, grad-students, post-grad students or visitor speakers on varied topics in pure and applied Mathematics that are beyond the scope of standard curriculum, with a purpose of giving more exposure to the students. > details Peer Discussion Sessions Open, drop-in peer math discussion sessions for undergraduates to clear out problems they encounter during coursework and beyond, as well as giving them a broader idea of Mathematics.</description></item><item><title>CMIT Foundation Anniversary</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/aficionados/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 14:47:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/aficionados/</guid><description>Anvesha Aficionados. The Science and Technology Council of IISER Thiruvananthapuram annually conducts Anvesha — the annual science fest of IISER Thiruvananthapuram. One of the major highlights of this fest is the science exhibition event, also known as Aficionados. Each year, CMIT organizes the Math Expo as part of Aficionados. During Anvesha 2021, CMIT conducted nine exibits, showcasing fascinating projects from students with unbeatable enthusiasm. The second issue of Donut brings to you an on-paper experience of all the exhibits at Aficionados 2021.</description></item><item><title>CMIT Foundation Anniversary</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/integrationbee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 14:47:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/integrationbee/</guid><description>Integration Bee. Integration Bee 2021 In association with the Science and Technology Council, the Club of Mathematics organizes the annual Integration Bee contest during the institute science fest, Anvesha. The winners of the contest are bestowed upon with the title of ‘Grand Integrator’ of the year and are awarded exciting cash prizes sponsored by the S&amp;T Council. The competition is a game of speed, accuracy, and control, which makes the event nail-biting exciting and a great deal of fun.</description></item><item><title>CMIT Foundation Anniversary</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/sn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 14:47:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/sn/</guid><description>The CMIT Foundation Anniversary. In September 2018, The Club of Mathematics, IISER Thiruvananthapuram (CMIT) was founded as a student-run, open mathematics club at the institute with objectives of providing an environment for the student community to discuss, learn and indulge in various activities throughout the year. Since then, CMIT has been an integral part of math enthusiasts at IISER Thiruvananthapuram. We have been organizing talk series, peer discussion sessions, math-based contests, and various other events to develop a community alongside regular academic curriculum.</description></item><item><title>CMIT Newsletter</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/newsletter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 14:47:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/newsletter/</guid><description>Donut &amp;#8212; The CMIT Newsletter. 'Donut' is the official newsletter from the Club of Mathematics, IISER Thiruvanathapuram. This is a platform to host interesting expository articles from diverse fields of mathematics, news from the latest at CMIT and math community, as well as recreational mathematics, tidbits, problems, and games — all packed in a visually creative flow. Donut is also a medium to develop an interactive community for exchange of mathematical interests.</description></item><item><title>Discord</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/discord/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 14:47:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/discord/</guid><description>The CMIT official Discord server. One principal motive of CMIT has always been to discuss about mathematics and help each other in the community. After the success of our first web-based discussion portal in 2020, we moved over to CMIT's own Discord server. The server has wonderful functionality alongside LaTeX support, dedicated reading groups, and various discussion channels. Comic: Calvin &amp;amp; Hobbes, copyright &amp;amp; all rights reserved by Bill Watterson and Andrews McMeel Universal.</description></item><item><title>Epiphany</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/epiphany/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 14:47:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/epiphany/</guid><description>Epiphany &amp;#8212; The CMIT Mathematics Tournament. Epiphany, the CMIT Mathematics Tournament is an annual pre-PhD level mathematics competition organised by the Club of Mathematics, IISER Thiruvananthapuram, in association with Anvesha. This is a student-run contest aimed at fostering interest in mathematics and providing an exciting platform to students to assess their skills. Epiphany is conducted as a part of $\pi$-Day celebrations each year. Epiphany 2.0: The Treasure Hunt As part of our $\pi$ week celebrations, CMIT in collaboration with Science and Technology Council, IISER Thiruvananthapuram, is organising 'Epiphany' after a long hiatus.</description></item><item><title>Events from SoM</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/som-events/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 14:47:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/som-events/</guid><description>Events from the SoM. This page is being built. It will soon be updated with the latest information.</description></item><item><title>Gallery</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/gallery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 14:47:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/gallery/</guid><description>Photographs from CMIT. This page is being built. It will soon be updated with the latest photos.</description></item><item><title>International Pi Day</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/piday/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 14:47:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/piday/</guid><description>International Pi Week 2022! Continuing our annual tradition of commemorating the most well-known mathematical constant π, CMIT is back with loads of events this year to celebrate International Pi Day 2022. Instead of restricting ourselves to a single day, this year, we have events happening for an entire week, starting from March 14th (Monday). CMIT $\pi$-uiz 3.0: One of CMIT's most awaited events, the fun, Math-themed quiz is back with its third edition.</description></item><item><title>Past Coordinators</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/about-past/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 14:47:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/about-past/</guid><description>CMIT coordinators in the past. Find the list of former CMIT coordinators below.
&lt; back Undergraduate Coordinators Ananthakrishna G "Abstract Nonsense to Applied Abstract Nonsense. Coffee, Karate and Poetry. Currently Pursuing Stacks. IISER Thiruvananthapuram BSMS Batch '17." Anand Chavan "I am a math major from Batch '17. I am fond of discussing mathematics in general. My interests are in Analysis, Geometry and Number theory." Kalin Krishna To be written. Akshita Mittal To be written.</description></item><item><title>Peer Discussions</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/peer-discussions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 14:47:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/peer-discussions/</guid><description>Peer Discussion Sessions. This page contains an information archive of all the peer discussion sessions that happened as a part of CMIT activities. These are open, drop-in peer math discussion sessions for undergraduates to clear out problems they encounter during coursework and beyond, as well as giving them a broader idea of Mathematics. Sessions are voluntarily mentored by senior students from the School of Mathematics.
Varsha 2021 November 16: Eighteenth Peer math discussion session for undergraduates.</description></item><item><title>S2</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/s2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 14:47:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/s2/</guid><description>$S^2$: CMIT's Second Foundation Anniversary. The club is turning two years old this September 28th, 2020. Over these years, we have been actively engaged to facilitate the growth of a mathematical community among students at the institute, and we look forward to a long way ahead. To commemorate this anniversary, we are hosting a mini online symposium and some fun online contests. What is $S^2$? &amp;nbsp; CMIT's foundation anniversary celebrations are called $S^n$, where $n$ stands for the $n^{th}$ anniversary&amp;trade;.</description></item><item><title>S3</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/s3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 14:47:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/s3/</guid><description>$S^3$: CMIT's Third Foundation Anniversary. Three years ago, on the 28th of September, 2018 the Club of Mathematics, IISER Thiruvananthapuram (CMIT), was founded with the intention of providing a platform for the students to discuss and learn where they felt free to express themselves. We also wanted to make it possible for them to indulge in various activities and events throughout the year. We have been organising talk series, peer discussion sessions, math-based contests, and various other events to facilitate a mathematical community among students at the institute, alongside the regular academic curriculum.</description></item><item><title>The Fourth BRICS Mathematics Conference</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/brics2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 14:47:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/brics2021/</guid><description>The Fourth BRICS Mathematics Conference. CMIT was extremely glad to be one of the local co-organizers of the fourth BRICS Mathematics conference at IISER Thiruvananthapuram alongside the School of Mathematics. The BRICS Mathematics Conference is an annual international event that aims to unite five countries whose mathematical schools are among world leaders, namely Brazil, Russia, India, China, and South Africa — to discuss and exchange ideas in various fields of Mathematics.</description></item><item><title>Two-part lecture series: Topology of a space from a random data sample | Extremal Morse critical points of a random distance function</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/blog/two-part-lecture-series-topology-of-a-space-from-a-random-data-sample/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/blog/two-part-lecture-series-topology-of-a-space-from-a-random-data-sample/</guid><description>It gives us immense pleasure to announce the next lecture in our ‘Two-part Lecture Series’, to be jointly hosted by CMIT and the School of Mathematics, IISER Thiruvananthapuram.
Kindly note that the two-part lectures will be delivered in a manner to cover the necessary basics in the first part of the talk, while the second part builds upon the same and continues.
This time, the two-part lecture will be delivered by Prof.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/contact/</guid><description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder **</description></item><item><title>Weekly Problem Contests</title><link>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/wpc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cmit.iisertvm.ac.in/wpc/</guid><description>Weekly Problem Contests (archived). CMIT hosted Weekly Problem Contests (WPC) where a set of problems were sent out as an open-to-all contest for students and asked for independent solution submissions. Innovative solutions were noted and published on our site. Note that copying total solutions from any source is heavily discouraged and destroys the objective of such a contest. You can submit your solutions (in any form of media) to mathsclub [at] iisertvm [dot] ac [dot] in with a subject line of the form “Solution Submission to Week X Problems”.</description></item></channel></rss>